

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

[(+84) 0328-491-676 | manhhungtran2308@gmail.com | manh-hung-portfolio | manhhung-fpt

Summary

Current Software Engineer at start-up crypto company Madarin Learning Labs. 1.5+ years experience specializing in the frontend and backend development, infrastructure automa- tion. I aim to keep up with trends in frontend design, best practices, tooling, and development to produce the best possible products. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools if the need arises. I also can communicate in English fluently (IELTS 6.0 - Reading 6.5).

Work Experience _____

One Mount Ho Chi Minh City

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Jun. 2023 - Aug. 2023

- Working according to Agile process, **CRM** Internal management provided the engineering of a microservice web application for spending, invoices, big data of customers, using charts and statistics to plan, market research direction for the company.
- Designed and implemented scalable APIs and background workers with Design-first approach for the project using front-end JavaScript library such as ReactJs, Next13, Typescript, TailwindCss, Zustand, etc.
- Professionally collaborate with other engineers to identify and reduce the number of bugs through unit tests and integration help in the user interface, CI/CD implementation with **Docker**, **Jenkins** pipeline. Task management with **Jira**, **Notion**.
- Design UI/UX interfaces from scratch files using Figma, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator.

Madarin Learning Labs. Co., Ltd.

Ho Chi Minh City

FRONT END DEVELOPER

Dec. 2022 - May. 2023

- Implementing and designing enterprise-level micro-service applications of Element Management System with latest technologies of ReactJs, Typescript, NextJs, The Graph, Chart.js, .NET 6 (MVC), NodeJs, MongoDB, TailwindCSS, Docker, AWS EC2.
- Provide a system for managing, processing and trading online courses, provide include Web3 Network Layer (EVM Blockchains Etherium), Presentation Layer (Ether.js), Defi (Uniswap), Indentify & Authentication (Metamask), Data (The Graph).
- Implemented several API microservices in the serverless AWS Lambda functions.
- Producing daily **Agile** progress and milestone updates directly to US customers with feature specification and designs for heavy exchanging data workload between devices, **REST API** server and user interface.
- · Improving code quality with pull requests, code reviews, unit/integration testing as well as debugging and fixing defects.
- Proficient in Git flow, Gitlabs, Devops with Docker Image, Compose, Jenkins pipeline. Task management with Jira, UI/UX interfaces from scratch files using Figma.

KMS Healthcare,Inc

Ho Chi Minh City

FRONT END DEVELOPER

Jun. 2022 - Aug. 2022

- Build an Al-based platform to check input and face data, perform graph tracking and performance using ReactJs, Redux, Sass, ChartJs and MongoDB.
- Design UI/UX interfaces from scratch files using Figma, Adobe Photoshop
- Included in the development of several products E2E from identifying system requirements and dependencies to workload balancing, software implementation, engineering, testing.
- · Worked directly with product admin to improve user's experience, define and fix software issues.

FPT Software Ho Chi Minh City

SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN

Dec. 2021 - Apr. 2022

- Provided the engineering of a microservice web application for users to manage profiles, subscriptions, and billing in terms of software deployment from scratch, which has been accepted for funding of FPT and is still growing fast.
- Designed and implemented scalable APIs and background workers with Design-first approach for the project using Java, .NET, SQL Server as database and front-end JavaScript library such as ReactJs,...
- · Design UI/UX interfaces from scratch files using Figma, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Animate
- Collaborated professionally with other engineers to identify and alleviate number of defects through unit tests as well as help with integration in user interface. Task management with **Trello**.

Honors & Awards

2022 1st Prize Technical Challenge Winner - KMS Fresher Bootcamp 2022

Ho Chi Minh City

2020 Top 5 English FPT's speaking contests

Ho Chi Minh City

Education

FPT University

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Ho Chi Minh City

Oct. 2019 - Apr. 2023

· Got a 30% FPT's Scholarship.

MMU University

Certificate. IN LEADING PROGRAM

Malaysia

Jan. 2020- Feb. 2020

JUNLY 06, 2023 HENRY TRAN · RÉSUMÉ 1